<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Gary Jaron_Find Your Way]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Gary Jaron_Find Your Way]]></description>
        <link>http://garyjaron.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 15:56:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://garyjaron.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 15:56:51 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Not all those who wander are lost.’]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f52ad2b4-a6f2-4f9d-967d-6656edd0e084.jpg">,<h1><em>‘Not all those who wander are lost.’</em></h1>,<p>J R R Tolkien, <em>The Lord of The Ring</em>, Book One, Chapter Ten, 2004 ed. p 170.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f52ad2b4-a6f2-4f9d-967d-6656edd0e084.jpg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7ae0d620-e3b9-47fd-ba69-1c9a6ff90ee6</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 18:50:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/e7cf7781-c125-45fc-af64-fa9d88a56f48.jpg">,<p>Building maps of the Territory using the fixed points of fact concerning birth and death.</p>,<p>If we follow the example of Descartes and try to find a single foundational fact of certainty. I think we should start with this question: Will you die?</p>,<p>I think there is not any reader or hearer of that question who will not answer in the affirmative, though they may wish to avoid the topic altogether. I think that we all know what the answer to that question is, though we may want to deny it, we may want to consider the question at all. We all know that we will one day die.</p>,<p>You and I will die.</p>,<p>The I of our voices, our song, will end. We will no longer be singing our song when we die. Into silence we will go. Our death’s mark the end point of our personal life continuum.</p>,<p>This simple and stark fixed point of certainty is one that we can build upon.</p>,<p>With the certainty of our death established, we can then acknowledge a second certainty. From the one comes the other, if it is a fact that we will die then it is a fact that we were born.</p>,<p>At the other end of our life’s continuum is our conception. Before we were born, we were silent. Out of silence and back into silence is our journey.</p>,<p>From those two facts, those two end points, and the linear flow of physical existence that is our lives in between, all else is built.</p>,<p>We are a physical body that was conceived, was born, and will one day die. Our first act of life is to cry out in pain. Our first song is pre-symbolic noise that erupts out of us as a reflex when our body is jump-started into taking our first breath outside of our mother’s womb. When we die, our song will end. Our last sound will be a pre-symbolic noise, a gasp as we take our last breath. Our life is lived in the time between our first breath and our last breath.</p>,<p>To understand the nature of how we understand reality is to focus in on those facts and build from those truths. What we can deduce from those facts of death and birth is that the physical universe has to exist to support those facts. It cannot be denied that if you were born and if you will die then all of that occurs in a real external and continuing physical reality that was there before you were born and will be there after you die.</p>,<p>[A version of this was first posted on August 28 2016]</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNkUFPwzAMhe_9FVGRWCutCSAhIdruMIkDl12AE0IoS5wt3ZpUcVqoEP8ddyuIWxx_es9-rrQdmNV1arZF8D6mq0rQ1yqpUAXbxVVmeqei9S7TS4ZLYnP2lTA2yMAaqk2DrGaa7yA-HKEFF3E9PsvdRraQYf569VYSbQ3L_jPr8VFnJJWzALEPbmJmIRVARpg5Uiipwa2mntVnjGNQVKZCKO8cqMiNVLD1_sAdRAHu_eVJoD7wBi8-zbY91teXAwSkJerhht-lkwzNzTsZyGPjNXDrEEJcg_EBsnmvvEy-M-1VP02yZItzIgt6_foVDZLPIs_LSsx5JUk1RaqOEvGUqvLtKZWUaRllsQ9g6nQfY4f3QsQ97ILVXFphrNPF6PtQfMhRzLTr285jJKXbv8v8ANFaj7U" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://garyjaron.com/building-maps-of-the-territory-using-the-fixed-points-of-fac/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5af9d35c-0c6e-413d-8ee7-5fdaa9e05810</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 16:18:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/acb1c708-9367-405d-96e9-848ec8eefccc.jpg">,<p>At birth, you are on the threshold of your true journey into the human community.</p>,<p>You are uncarved blocks awaiting artisans’ hands and insights.</p>,<p>From the moment of creation, you are potential.</p>,<p>At that moment, how you unfold and where you will wander was shaped by unseen factors.</p>,<p>But not unknowable.</p>,<p>The shaping by those factors is hidden deep in the darkness of your unconscious minds.</p>,<p>If we truly want to know ourselves, you need to bring those factors that shaped you into the light of your conscious mind. By doing this, you can make conscious use of them to change who you are and to help you to find your way.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://garyjaron.com/at-birth-you-are-on-the-threshold-of-your-true-journey-into/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">58db2208-3b50-47d0-bc07-3ff8d884966e</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 17:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When you are born you are potential.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/2eb5ab68-7d20-43d2-b0b7-e76d0adab3c4.jpg">,<h2><em>When you are born you are potential.</em></h2>,<p>You feel but have no means to understand those feelings.</p>,<p>Understanding requires and awaits the acquisition of a
symbol set such as language.</p>,<p>Once we acquire language we have the tools to describe to
ourselves what we experience.</p>,<p>Hence our primary experience is of non-symbolic feelings and
emotions.</p>,<p>This is the stuff upon which all else is built.</p>,<p>Our primary maps of the world are built out of feelings and
emotions.</p>,<p>To study and understand this primary map making process you
can watch and study infants or animals.</p>,<p>Animals remain on the level of feelings and emotions and
manage to survive and thrive without the aid of any symbol systems. </p>,<p>Even when we acquire complex symbol systems and the skill to
use them, our first and primary mode of being is on the silent level of
feelings and emotions.</p>,<p>Our first maps of the Territory are non-symbolic.</p>,<p>Language and language processing is always a secondary
mental process, it is never the primary one.</p>,<p>Our elaborate symbol systems to describe and explain the
workings of the Territory are always mere finite static attempts to describe
something that is really all happening on a non-symbolic dynamic fluid
undifferentiated continuous infinite level.</p>,<p>William James called this “the buzzing blooming confusion”.</p>,<p>‘<em>The baby, assailed by eyes, ears, nose, skin, and entrails
at once, feels it all as one great blooming, buzzing confusion; and to the very
end of life, our location of all things in one space is due to the fact that
the original extents or bignesses of all the sensations which came to our
notice at once, coalesced together into one and the same space. There is no
other reason than this why "the hand I touch and see coincides spatially
with the hand I immediately feel</em>." [William James, The Principles of
Psychology, 1890, chapter XIII, Discrimination and Comparison, ]</p>,<p><a href="http://psychclassics.yorku.ca/James/Principles/prin13.htm" title="">William James, The Principles of Psychology</a></p>]]></description>
            <link>http://garyjaron.com/when-you-are-born-you-are-potential/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5724cb9f-a639-43d9-ac78-c50b83b21ab2</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 23:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[General Comments….?  Put them here!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2><em><strong>General Comments….?  Put them here!</strong></em></h2>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/45e80a67-de2e-4e3e-9301-4f0979226522.jpg">,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNkUFPwzAMhe_9FVGRWCutCSAhIdruMIkDl12AE0IoS5wt3ZpUsVuoEP-ddOskbnH86T37udJ2YFbXqdkWwXtKV5WIX6ukQhVsR6vM9E6R9S7TS4bLyObsJ2FskIE1sTYNspppvgN6OkILjnA9vsrdRraQYf5-81FG2hqW_WfW47POolTOAlAf3MTMQiqAJJi5qFDGBrc69qw-YxyDimUqhPLOgSJupIKt9wfugAS4z7cXgfrAG7z6Ntv2WN9eDxAwLlEPd_whnWTi3LyTIXpsvAZuHUKgNRgfIJv3ysvkN9Ne9dMkS7Y4J7KIr4tf0WD0WeR5WYk5rySppkjVUSKeUlW-PaWSMi1JFvsApk73RB0-CkF72AWrubTCWKeL0feh-JKjmGnXt51Hikr3l8v8AUGlj6s" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNkUFPwzAMhe_9FVGRWCutCSAhIdruMIkDl12AE0IoS5wt3ZpUsVuoEP-ddOskbnH86T37udJ2YFbXqdkWwXtKV5WIX6ukQhVsR6vM9E6R9S7TS4bLyObsJ2FskIE1sTYNspppvgN6OkILjnA9vsrdRraQYf5-81FG2hqW_WfW47POolTOAlAf3MTMQiqAJJi5qFDGBrc69qw-YxyDimUqhPLOgSJupIKt9wfugAS4z7cXgfrAG7z6Ntv2WN9eDxAwLlEPd_whnWTi3LyTIXpsvAZuHUKgNRgfIJv3ysvkN9Ne9dMkS7Y4J7KIr4tf0WD0WeR5WYk5rySppkjVUSKeUlW-PaWSMi1JFvsApk73RB0-CkF72AWrubTCWKeL0feh-JKjmGnXt51Hikr3l8v8AUGlj6s</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">387709fa-e219-46ed-acbe-8851220a047c</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:35:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/afcba68e-f0a8-4636-9893-a61ece84b66f.jpg">,<p>Understanding the idea of a Deity with limited power/ability.</p>,<p>April 25, 2017</p>,<p>Pantheism = Assumption that the deity is modeled on the biological workings of a human being. It has a body that has the emergent property/ability that we can call a mind/soul/spirt. The deity is the mind/soul/spirit of the universe.&nbsp; (Henceforth
for the sake of this discussion, I will refer to this attribute by the term ‘mind’.)</p>,<p>1)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Fact: The human body and the human mind relationship is one in which the mind has only limited control over all aspects of the body.
</p>,<p>2)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Therefore, based on this analogy, the mind of the universe has limited control over the body of the universe.</p>,<p>Panentheism = Assumption that the deity is again modeled on the biology of a human being. Now a further assumption is that there are two entities. One entity is a body (aka the universe) and the other a mind that is different and separate from the body. (Note: I have just create a cosmic version of the ‘mind – body problem’; refer to Descartes, for one
example, for some of those issues and problems.)</p>,<p>1)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Next assumption: the deity’s mind controls completely its body and all its workings. Another way to say ‘complete control’ is to say that this deity is/has omniscience and omnipotence. </p>,<p>2)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Next assumption: The deity is the source of Goodness, Kindness, Justice, Love, etc. As in the deity as described by Christianity, Islam, or Judaism.</p>,<p>a.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Results in the problem of Evil aka Theodicy.</p>,<p>3)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To resolve the problem of Evil/Theodicy replace assumption #1 with: &nbsp;this mind only partial or has limited control over its body.</p>,<p>&nbsp;A) That results in no problem of Evil. Evil is simply what occurs when events take place that the mind doesn’t like and cannot either foresee and/or lacks the ability to do anything about, due to the inherent limits of mind’s control over the body.</p>,<p>Therefore, to avoid the whole Evil problem you posit either the Pantheistic deity modeled on the human body or you posit the Panentheistic limited deity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://garyjaron.com/understanding-the-idea-of-a-deity-with-limited-powerability/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bb1bb665-c5db-4c00-afd0-ffa3fffc7daf</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 15:54:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Universe and Cosmos]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/c06d52ca-bf8a-4b34-a09e-fe9b4502e47d.jpg">,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/b2df0f1a-b651-45bb-a6b1-b7711707faec.jpg">,<h2>Universe and Cosmos</h2>,<p>March 26, 2017</p>,<p>To simple word for everything that exists but the differences between them are interesting and significant. </p>,<p>Let’s start with the seemingly easier term, universe.</p>,<p>The word <em>universe</em> points toward the totality of physical stuff that is studied by scientists on the grand scale in the fields of astronomy and cosmology. When scientists deal with the study of the workings of this grand collection of stuff they are dealing in the study of astrophysics and physics. When they are dealing our corner of the universe then they are
studying geology, ecology, weather, biology, and chemistry.</p>,<p>Hopefully those brief lists, though they may be incomplete give you a rough idea of what I am talking about. The universe is physical stuff and the interaction of that physical stuff that can be quantified, and studied with the senses and tools that augment our senses.</p>,<p>The study of the universe generates a vast collection of facts; perhaps an infinite collection of facts can be gathered and accumulated by all this study.</p>,<p>Albert Camus in his 1942 novel <em>The Stranger</em>, near the end of that novel, Camus wrote a phrase that is very descriptive concerning the relationship of the universe and humanity; ‘<em>gazing up at the dark sky spangled with its signs and stars, for the first time, the first, I laid my heart open to the benign indifference of the universe.</em>’ [As translated into
English by Stuart Gilbert]</p>,<p>I take from this quote the meaning that for some people, and this would be true of the scientific worldview in particular, the universe lacks the capacity to concern itself with any specific aspect of itself, let alone take notice of the activities of humanity. The universe as a collective entity is indifferent to what occurs within itself.</p>,<p>Let us begin to move toward explaining the word <em>cosmos</em>.</p>,<p>We can start with a quote from Aristotle, ‘All men by nature desire to know.’ (Metaphysics, 1.1, 980211-7)</p>,<p>The desire to understand the workings everything is what drives the scientist and the philosopher.</p>,<p>Most important of all and underneath it all for the philosopher and the scientist is the belief that the universe is orderly and that we can by observation and reason understand that order.</p>,<p>That belief is a state of faith. It is not directly provable but is indirectly ‘proven’ by all that the scientist and the philosopher does and tries to do in their respective endeavors.</p>,<p>Both the scientist and the philosopher believe that work proves and justifies their faith that the universe is orderly and knowable.</p>,<p>That belief begins to move us from quantifiable facts about the universe to qualitative ideas concerning cosmos.</p>,<p>Cosmos is the belief that the universe is meaningful and a source of meaning.</p>,<p>Cosmos is the belief that there is meaning and purpose to be found in the order and activities of the natural universe.</p>,<p>When we create, conjure, invoke, assume and project meaning into and towards the universe we have transformed it into cosmos.</p>,<ol><li><em>The cosmos(<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/British_English" title="British English">UK</a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help:IPA_for_English" title="Help:IPA for English">/ˈkɒzmɒs/</a>,<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_English" title="American English">US</a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help:IPA_for_English" title="Help:IPA for English">/ˈkɒzmoʊs/</a>) is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universe" title="Universe">universe </a>regarded as a complex and orderly system; the opposite of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chaos_(cosmogony)" title="Chaos (cosmogony)">chaos</a>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosopher" title="Philosopher">philosopher</a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pythagoras" title="Pythagoras">Pythagoras </a>used the term cosmos (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Greek" title="Ancient Greek">Ancient Greek</a>:κόσμος) for the order of the universe, but the term was not part of modern language until the 19th century geographer and polymath, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_von_Humboldt" title="Alexander von Humboldt">Alexander von Humboldt</a>, resurrected the use of the word from the ancient Greek, assigned it to his multi-volume treatise, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kosmos_(Humboldt)" title="Kosmos (Humboldt)">Kosmos</a>, which influenced modern and somewhat <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holism" title="Holism">holistic</a> perception of the universe as one interacting entity. [source: </em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos " title="">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos</a><em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos " title=""></a>]</em></li></ol>]]></description>
            <link>http://garyjaron.com/universe-and-cosmos/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c88286a6-afa8-4870-87d6-2806e1e7b2ac</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 15:03:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Protagoras, a Greek Sophist philosopher wrote:]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cc728c5f-16c8-4813-a8da-4d6786a807a4.jpg">,<p>The Measure of all things?</p>,<h2>Protagoras, a Greek Sophist philosopher wrote:</h2>,<h2><strong>“</strong><em><strong>Humans are the measure of all things"</strong></em>.</h2>,<p>This quotation is restated in Plato's <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theaetetus_(dialogue)" title="Theaetetus (dialogue)">Theaetetus </a></em>at <a href="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/cgi-bin/ptext?lookup=Plat.+Theaet.+152a">152a</a>. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sextus_Empiricus" title="Sextus Empiricus">Sextus Empiricus </a>gives a direct quotation in<em>Adv. math.</em>7.60: πάντων χρημάτων μέτρον ἐστὶν ἄνθρωπος, τῶν μὲν ὄντων ὡς ἔστιν, τῶν δὲ οὐκ ὄντων ὡς οὐκ ἔστιν. ... Similarly, in Ancient Greek, Protagoras used the Greek word <em>anthrōpos </em>(<em>human being, person</em>), making a general statement about human beings.</p>,<p>What I think the phrase means is that it reveals that we understand the world through the lens of our own perspective. The world is experienced on a non-verbal direct sensory level. However, once we begin to process that non-verbal data we select and transform it into our human symbols systems. Hence we are the measuring tool that forces all things to conform to. We only understand the world through this process of selection and interpretation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://garyjaron.com/protagoras-a-greek-sophist-philosopher-wrote/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">af824c14-152a-4069-b877-19bd6456e46f</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 18:50:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/29a1f53f-829f-4001-a041-b48d99a363e8.jpg">,<p>My Meetings with Remarkable Books</p>,<p>Here is a semi-random listing of books for you to wander through… (remember to use your browser’s back arrow to return to this website page.)</p>,<p><strong>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance by Robert M. Pirsig, 1974</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen_and_the_Art_of_Motorcycle_Maintenance">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zen_and_the_Art_of_Motorcycle_Maintenance</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Zen-Art-Motorcycle-Maintenance-Inquiry/dp/0060589469/ref=mt_paperback?_encoding=UTF8&amp;me">https://www.amazon.com/Zen-Art-Motorcycle-Maintenance-Inquiry/dp/0060589469/ref=mt_paperback?_encoding=UTF8&amp;me</a>=</p>,<p><strong>Man’s Search for Meaning by Viktor E. Frankl, 1946/1959 English Translation</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man%27s_Search_for_Meaning">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man%27s_Search_for_Meaning</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mans-Search-Meaning-Viktor-Frankl/dp/0807014273/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr">https://www.amazon.com/Mans-Search-Meaning-Viktor-Frankl/dp/0807014273/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr</a>=</p>,<p><strong>The Psychology of Consciousness by Robert E. Ornstein, 1972</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Psychology-Consciousness-Robert-E-Ornstein/dp/0155730827/ref=la_B001HNIW0O_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1475440119&amp;sr=1-4">https://www.amazon.com/Psychology-Consciousness-Robert-E-Ornstein/dp/0155730827/ref=la_B001HNIW0O_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1475440119&amp;sr=1-4</a></p>,<p><strong>The True Believer by Eric Hoffer, 1951</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_True_Believer">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_True_Believer</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B003TO5838/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B003TO5838/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1</a></p>,<p><strong>The Social Construction of Reality by Peter L. Berger and Thomas Luckmann, 1966</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Social_Construction_of_Reality">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Social_Construction_of_Reality</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Social-Construction-Reality-Sociology-Knowledge-ebook/dp/B004X36R6G">https://www.amazon.com/Social-Construction-Reality-Sociology-Knowledge-ebook/dp/B004X36R6G</a></p>,<p><strong>The Sacred Canopy by Peter L. Berger, 1967</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B004X3789G/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B004X3789G/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1</a></p>,<p><strong>The Act of Creation by Arthur Koestler, 1964</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Act_of_Creation">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Act_of_Creation</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Act-Creation-Arkana-Arthur-Koestler/dp/0140191917">https://www.amazon.com/Act-Creation-Arkana-Arthur-Koestler/dp/0140191917</a></p>,<p><strong>The Ghost in the Machine by Arthur Koestler, 1967</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ghost_in_the_Machine">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ghost_in_the_Machine</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ghost-Machine-Arkana-Arthur-Koestler/dp/0140191925">https://www.amazon.com/Ghost-Machine-Arkana-Arthur-Koestler/dp/0140191925</a></p>,<p><strong>Metaphors We Live By by George Lakoff and Mark Johnson, 1980</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_metaphor">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conceptual_metaphor</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Metaphors-We-Live-George-Lakoff/dp/0226468011">https://www.amazon.com/Metaphors-We-Live-George-Lakoff/dp/0226468011</a></p>,<p><strong>Philosophy in the Flesh by George Lakoff and Mark Johnson, 1999</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001FSJAWK/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001FSJAWK/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1</a></p>,<p><strong>Saving the Appearances by Owen Barfield, 1957</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saving_the_Appearances:_A_Study_in_Idolatry">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saving_the_Appearances:_A_Study_in_Idolatry</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Saving-Appearances-Idolatry-Owen-Barfield/dp/081956205X">https://www.amazon.com/Saving-Appearances-Idolatry-Owen-Barfield/dp/081956205X</a></p>,<p><strong>Science and the Modern World by Alfred North Whitehead, 1925</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Science-Modern-World-Alfred-Whitehead/dp/0684836394">https://www.amazon.com/Science-Modern-World-Alfred-Whitehead/dp/0684836394</a></p>,<p><strong>The Structure of Scientific Revolutions by Thomas S. Kuhn, 1962</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Structure_of_Scientific_Revolutions">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Structure_of_Scientific_Revolutions</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Structure-Scientific-Revolutions-Thomas-Kuhn/dp/0226458083">https://www.amazon.com/Structure-Scientific-Revolutions-Thomas-Kuhn/dp/0226458083</a></p>,<p><strong>The Passion of the Western Mind by Richard Tarnas, 1991</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Passion_of_the_Western_Mind">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Passion_of_the_Western_Mind</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005PRJQQM/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005PRJQQM/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1</a></p>,<p><strong>The Tao Te Ching: A New Translation with Commentary by Ellen M. Chen, 1989</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0099D4EMO/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0099D4EMO/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1</a></p>,<p><strong>Tao: The Watercourse Way by Alan Watts, 1975</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tao:_The_Watercourse_Way">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tao:_The_Watercourse_Way</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tao-Watercourse-Way-Alan-Watts/dp/0394733118">https://www.amazon.com/Tao-Watercourse-Way-Alan-Watts/dp/0394733118</a></p>,<p><strong>The Tao of Pooh by Benjamin Hoff, 1982</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tao_of_Pooh">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tao_of_Pooh</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tao-Pooh-Benjamin-Hoff/dp/0140067477">https://www.amazon.com/Tao-Pooh-Benjamin-Hoff/dp/0140067477</a></p>,<p><strong>Aristotle: The Desire to Understand by Jonathan Lear, 1988</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aristotle-Desire-Understand-Jonathan-Lear/dp/0521347629">https://www.amazon.com/Aristotle-Desire-Understand-Jonathan-Lear/dp/0521347629</a></p>,<p><strong>The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown of the Bicameral Mind by Julian Jaynes, 1976</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bicameralism_(psychology)">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bicameralism_(psychology)</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Origin-Consciousness-Breakdown-Bicameral-Mind/dp/1501277227">https://www.amazon.com/Origin-Consciousness-Breakdown-Bicameral-Mind/dp/1501277227</a></p>,<p><strong>Science and Sanity by Alfred Korzybski, 1933</strong></p>,<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfred_Korzybski">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfred_Korzybski</a></p>,<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Science-Sanity-Introduction-Non-Aristotelian-Semantics/dp/0937298018">https://www.amazon.com/Science-Sanity-Introduction-Non-Aristotelian-Semantics/dp/0937298018</a></p>,<p>These are some of the books I will be referring to on this Blog.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxLz89Pz0nVLc4sSdUtSy3KTMtMTizJzM-zUkgHy6QZGJibWxolpiUapaUlWaTpZZTk5gAAFVcTDw</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2a498e03-ab8f-449d-b8af-dadf05d1a330</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 18:58:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>